Nadia Abby

abby.nadia76@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/nadia-abby/ | https://github.com/Nadia27 | www.nadiaabby.com

(404) 457- 6137 | Snellville, Georgia

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in Electronics and Communications. With proven experience in troubleshooting complex technical problems using critical thinking and technical expertise. An expert at creating and implementing solutions to improve workflow and maximize efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, C#, Github, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, React.js, Heroku, Java, API, AJAX, Bootstrap, Node.js, Google Firebase, Version Control, Redux, PHP, Python

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Perfect Fit Resources https://perfect-fit-autism.herokuapp.com/

- Built using a MySQL database, Google Firebase, Bootstrap, and more.
- A community resource application aimed to aid the Autism community with connecting with community approved resources.
- Role: backend development i.e, creating database & research

StartGrow https://fathomless-badlands-78206.herokuapp.com/ (currently in development)

- React/Redux application built with Node.js, MongoDB, and more.
- Connecting startup owners with customers through surveys sent via email.
- Sole developer

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NCR (Volt Contractor) - Repair Technician 2016

MAY 2014 - JANUARY

- Dynamic and influential team member in the Mobile Device Management Lab
- Assisted other team members in meeting daily and weekly productivity goals
- Implemented office design to help create a more efficient workflow
- Restructured Sephora account processes to decrease product repair turnaround time
- Diagnosed and repaired equipment malfunctions, using test equipment/software while reducing product downtime

SPC International - Repair Technician

January 2014 - May 2014

- Increased workflow efficiency by improving documentation system
- Managed daily repair schedule resulting in 100% daily completion of productivity goals

Repaired/refurbished switch mode power supply

TeligentEMS - Surface Mount Technician Offline Setup Operator **2011**

October 2010 - April

- Wired and soldered PCB circuit boards according to schematics
- Programmed and assisted in the setup, and the debug of equipment
- Resolved shortages i.e missing parts or incorrect quantities
- Loaded feeders using setup sheets with proper part orientations

United States Navy- Aviation Ordnanceman 3rd Class

August 2003 - August 2007

- Implemented and managed training program for 100+ sailors.
- Supervise and provide guidance to 8 specialists during weapons assembly
- Attention to detail, extreme accuracy, and thoroughness required to complete daily tasks
- Performed troubleshooting, fault isolation, and repair from system to component level

EDUCATION

edX - HarvardX October 2018 - Current

CS50, Introduction to Computer Science

1 Million Women to Tech July 2018 - October 2018

Summer of Code, Python & JavaScript

Georgia Institute of Technology November 2017 - May

2018

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development

ITT Technical Institute September 2008 - September

2013

Bachelor of Science, Electronics and Communications Engineering Technology